<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News | Shen Lab@NTU</title>
    <link>https://shen-lab.org/research_brief/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://shen-lab.org/research_brief/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>News</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://shen-lab.org/media/logo_hu5606885a69ebc720faad867579aa5b55_46386_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://shen-lab.org/research_brief/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>💻 ⌚ 🧬 Multi-Omics Data Integration</title>
      <link>https://shen-lab.org/research_brief/multi-omics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shen-lab.org/research_brief/multi-omics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our lab&amp;rsquo;s research focuses on integrating multi-omics and wearable data to advance the field of precision medicine, with a special emphasis on understanding the intricate interplay between the microbiome and metabolome. Our research likely involves analyzing how the microbiome affects the metabolome and vice versa. For instance, certain metabolites produced by the microbiome can impact human metabolic pathways, while changes in the host&amp;rsquo;s metabolism can alter the microbiome composition. Understanding this bidirectional relationship is crucial for developing targeted therapeutic strategies. The ultimate goal of our lab&amp;rsquo;s research is to use the integrated data from multi-omics and wearables for precision medicine. By understanding the complex interactions between the microbiome and metabolome, and how they relate to individual physiological states, our aim to develop personalized healthcare strategies. This could involve tailored dietary recommendations, customized probiotic or prebiotic therapies, or specific drug treatments based on an individual&amp;rsquo;s unique microbiome-metabolome profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lab&amp;rsquo;s research focuses on integrating multi-omics and wearable data to advance the field of precision medicine, with a special emphasis on understanding the intricate interplay between the microbiome and metabolome. Our research likely involves analyzing how the microbiome affects the metabolome and vice versa. For instance, certain metabolites produced by the microbiome can impact human metabolic pathways, while changes in the host&amp;rsquo;s metabolism can alter the microbiome composition. Understanding this bidirectional relationship is crucial for developing targeted therapeutic strategies. The ultimate goal of our lab&amp;rsquo;s research is to use the integrated data from multi-omics and wearables for precision medicine. By understanding the complex interactions between the microbiome and metabolome, and how they relate to individual physiological states, our aim to develop personalized healthcare strategies. This could involve tailored dietary recommendations, customized probiotic or prebiotic therapies, or specific drug treatments based on an individual&amp;rsquo;s unique microbiome-metabolome profile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🧑 Aging and Aging-Related Diseases</title>
      <link>https://shen-lab.org/research_brief/aging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shen-lab.org/research_brief/aging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aging is a complex biological process characterized by a gradual decline in physiological functions, which increases susceptibility to diseases and death. This process is influenced by a myriad of genetic, environmental, and lifestyle factors. Our research on aging and aging-related diseases like AD and PD is utilizing multi-omics and wearable technology to gain a comprehensive understanding of the aging process. The ultimate goal of our research is to develop predictive models for aging and aging-related diseases. These models aim to integrate multi-omics data with information from wearable devices, along with clinical and demographic information. Machine learning and artificial intelligence algorithms are employed to analyze this vast and complex dataset, with the objective of identifying patterns and predictive biomarkers. In summary, our lab&amp;rsquo;s research represents a cutting-edge, interdisciplinary approach to studying aging, leveraging the power of multi-omics and wearable technology to build comprehensive predictive models for aging and its related diseases. This research not only deepens our understanding of the biological processes of aging but also holds promise for improving health outcomes in the aging population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aging is a complex biological process characterized by a gradual decline in physiological functions, which increases susceptibility to diseases and death. This process is influenced by a myriad of genetic, environmental, and lifestyle factors. Our research on aging and aging-related diseases like AD and PD is utilizing multi-omics and wearable technology to gain a comprehensive understanding of the aging process. The ultimate goal of our research is to develop predictive models for aging and aging-related diseases. These models aim to integrate multi-omics data with information from wearable devices, along with clinical and demographic information. Machine learning and artificial intelligence algorithms are employed to analyze this vast and complex dataset, with the objective of identifying patterns and predictive biomarkers. In summary, our lab&amp;rsquo;s research represents a cutting-edge, interdisciplinary approach to studying aging, leveraging the power of multi-omics and wearable technology to build comprehensive predictive models for aging and its related diseases. This research not only deepens our understanding of the biological processes of aging but also holds promise for improving health outcomes in the aging population.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🤰 Maternal and Child Health 👶</title>
      <link>https://shen-lab.org/research_brief/pregnancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shen-lab.org/research_brief/pregnancy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maternal and Child Health (MCH) is a critical public health domain focused on the health and well-being of mothers and children. Our lab&amp;rsquo;s research in Maternal and Child Health, particularly concerning preterm birth, is employing multi-omics and wearable technology to deepen understanding and improve outcomes. Our lab is likely integrating data from these multi-omics analyses with information collected from wearable devices to create a comprehensive picture of maternal and fetal health. This integrated approach can identify patterns and risk factors associated with preterm birth and other pregnancy-related complications. Advanced data analysis techniques, including machine learning and AI, are used to analyze these complex datasets, aiming to develop predictive models for adverse pregnancy outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maternal and Child Health (MCH) is a critical public health domain focused on the health and well-being of mothers and children. Within this field, one significant area of concern is preterm birth, defined as the delivery of a baby before 37 weeks of gestation. Preterm birth is a leading cause of neonatal mortality and can have long-term impacts on health and development. Factors contributing to preterm birth are multifaceted, encompassing genetic, environmental, socioeconomic, and healthcare-related aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your lab&amp;rsquo;s research in Maternal and Child Health, particularly concerning preterm birth, is employing multi-omics and wearable technology to deepen understanding and improve outcomes. Multi-omics, encompassing genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, metabolomics, and microbiomics, offers a comprehensive approach to unraveling the complex biological mechanisms underlying pregnancy, including the risk factors and pathways leading to preterm birth. This approach allows for the identification of biomarkers and potential therapeutic targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, genomics can provide insights into genetic predispositions to preterm birth, while transcriptomics and proteomics can reveal changes in gene expression and protein levels associated with pregnancy complications. Metabolomics offers a snapshot of metabolic changes during pregnancy, and microbiomics sheds light on the role of the microbiome in maternal and fetal health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In tandem, wearable technology is increasingly being utilized in MCH research. Wearables, such as smartwatches and fitness trackers, can continuously monitor vital signs like heart rate, sleep patterns, and physical activity. More advanced wearables can track physiological parameters specific to pregnancy, such as uterine activity or fetal heart rate. This real-time monitoring can help in early detection of abnormalities, leading to timely interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your lab is likely integrating data from these multi-omics analyses with information collected from wearable devices to create a comprehensive picture of maternal and fetal health. This integrated approach can identify patterns and risk factors associated with preterm birth and other pregnancy-related complications. Advanced data analysis techniques, including machine learning and AI, are used to analyze these complex datasets, aiming to develop predictive models for adverse pregnancy outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, your lab&amp;rsquo;s research in Maternal and Child Health using multi-omics and wearables aims to advance our understanding of the biological, physiological, and environmental factors influencing maternal and fetal health. This research holds the potential for earlier identification of at-risk pregnancies, personalized healthcare strategies, and improved outcomes for mothers and children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
